Mss.B.L493
American Philosophical Society
- Correspondence, 7.0 Linear feet 17 upright boxes, 1 oversized folder, 1 digital record. (Box 1-17)
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Dec. 5, 1844; 9-1/4x5-3/4; Glasewald
    Cassel, A.L.S. 3p. In German. (see Le Conte papers.) Forwards minerals and wishes to continue exchanging minerals for U.S.insects. Refers to Philippi. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [John] L. Le Conte, New York, Dec. 24, 1844; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Dunker, Wilhelm, 1809-1885
    Cassel, A.L.S. 3p.and add. (see Le Conte papers.) Proposes exchange of minerals for shells. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, New York, March 15, 1845; 10x8; Aall, Nicolai
    Norway, A.L.S. 2p. In Norwegian. (see Le Conte papers.) Originally B. L493.2.
  - Letter to John [Eatton] Le Conte, New York, July 17, 1845; 10x7-3/4; Hope, Frederick William, 1797-1862
    London, A.L.S. 3p.and add. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomology. Natural history. Originally B L493.3
  - Letter to Charles J. Peterson, Philadelphia, Sept. 19, 1845; 9-3/4x8; Peterson, Thomas, 1791-1854
    Providence, R.I., A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Le Conte papers.) Cannot accept his invitation. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [John Eatton] Le Conte, New York, March 15, 1846; 9x7; Hope, Frederick William, 1797-1862
    London, A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomology. Must travel for his wife's health. Originally B L493.3
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], March 20, 1846; 9-3/4x8; Zimmerman, C.
    Columbia, S.C., A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Glad he returned home safely. Entomology. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], May 14, 1846; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Dunker, Wilhelm, 1809-1885
    Cassel, A.L.S. 3p. In German. (see Le Conte papers.) Concerning the exchange of minerals for shells. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to John L[awrence] Le Conte, New York, May 30, 1846; 10-1/2x8-3/4; Gruner, E. Chre L.
    Bremen, A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see Le Conte papers.) Forwards minerals. Formerly B L493.3
  - Letter to [J.L. ?] Leconte, June 23, 1846; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Zimmerman, C.
    Columbia, S. C., A.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, July 20, 1846; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    Columbia, Pa., A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Is ill and cannot go with him. Has been to Washington, studying phonology of the Comanches, etc. Refers to Leidy and botanical subject. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to John [L.] Leconte, Aug. 5, 1846; 8" x 10"; Zimmerman, C.
    Columbia, S.C., A.L.S. 3p. and add.
  - Letter to [J.L. ?] Leconte, Aug. 20, 1846; 8" x 10"; Zimmerman, C.
    Columbia, S.C., A.L.S. 4p.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Oct. 24, 1846; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    Columbia, A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomological studies. Refers to Agassiz and Baird. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to John [L. Le Conte], Nov. 10, 1846; 10x8; Lawrence, Eugene, 1823-1894
    Cambridge Mass., A.L.S. 3p. (see Le Conte papers.) Concerning his entomological researches News of Boston and surroundings. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to John L. Leconte, Dec. 5, 1846; 7 1/2" x 10"; Harris, Thaddeus William, 1795-1856
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 4p., add.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], Dec. 10, 1846; 8" x 10"; Zimmerman, C.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, New York, Dec. 21, 1846; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    A.L.S. 4p.,add. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomology. Natural history. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to Charles Wilkes, March 7, 1847; 10x8; Le Conte, John L. (John Lawrence), 1825-1883
    New York, A.L.S. 3p. Draft. (see Le Conte papers.) Concerning identification of insects collected on the expedition. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, March 24, 1847; 8" x 10"; Zimmerman, C.
  - Agreement with Charles Wilkes to identify coleoptera found on exploring expedition, March 25, 1847; 10x8; Le Conte, John L. (John Lawrence), 1825-1883
    New York, A.D.S. 1p. Draft. (see Le Conte papers.) Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to Charles Wilkes, March 31, 1847; 10x8; Le Conte, John L. (John Lawrence), 1825-1883
    Washington, A.L.S. 3p. Draft. (see Le Conte papers.) Concerning identification of coleoptera collected on exploring expedition. Originally B L493.2
  - Statement of expenditures to the Library committee of Congress, March 31, 1847; 10x8; Le Conte, John L. (John Lawrence), 1825-1883
    Washington, A.D.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Originally B L493.3
  - Letter to John L. Leconte, April 6, 1847; 8" x 10"; Zimmerman, C.
    Columbia, S.C., A.L.S. 2p. and add.
  - Letter to [Charles Wilkes], April 28, 1847; 10x8; Le Conte, John L. (John Lawrence), 1825-1883
    New York, A.L. 2p. Draft. (see Le Conte papers.) Needs certain publications to catalogue coleoptera found on exploring expedition. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, May 1, 1847; 10x8; Drayton, G.
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Forwards money. Suggests that he get all drawings of insects done and numbered. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to John [L.] Le Conte, New York, May 9, 1847; 10x8; Wilkes, Charles, 1798-1877
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Le Conte papers.) Concerning books he needs for identification of coleoptera from exploring expedition. Concerning drawings and engravings for publication. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to Charles Wilkes, Washington, June 16, 1847; 10x8; Le Conte, John L. (John Lawrence), 1825-1883
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. Draft. (see Le Conte papers.) Asks for books from Library of Congress to help him in identifying coleoptera collected on exploring expedition. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [John L.] LeConte, June 16, 1847; 8x9-3/4; Blandy, Alfred A.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], June 21, 1847; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Zimmerman, C.
    Columbia, A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Leconte, New York, July 6, 1847; 10x7-3/4; Brevoort, James Carson, 1818-1887
    A.L.S. 4p.,add. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomology. Fishes. Mollusks. Located living Trilobite, and wants Agassiz informed. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, July 16, 1847; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Zimmerman, C.
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, Sept. 6, 1847; 8" x 10"; Zimmerman, C.
    Columbia, S.C., A.L.S. 5p. and add.
  - Letter to [John E.] Le Conte, Nov. 10, 1847; 10x7-1/2; De Kay, James E. (James Ellsworth), 1792-1851
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Concerning crustaceans of New York.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Nov. 23, 1847; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Melsheimer, Friedrich Ernst, 1782-1873
    Dover, Pa., A.L.S. 4p.
  - Letter to J[ohn L.] LeConte, Nov. 29, 1847; 9x11; Engelmann, George, 1809-1884
    Discussion of insects collected by others, and the disposition of their collections.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Dec. 3, 1847; 8-3/4x7; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    A.L.S. 3p.and add. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomology, with especial reference to Schaum and Agassiz. Fossil bones. Refers to the APS and academy of natural sciences of Philadelphia.
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, Dec. 12, 1847; 8x5; Newberry, J. S., (John Strong), 1822-1892
    New York, A.L.S. 4p. (see Le Conte papers Geology of the West.
  - Letter to [J.L. ?] Le Conte, Dec. 28, 1847; 7" x 8 3/4"; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    A.L.S. 2p.
  - Accounts of income from various sources, 1847-1859; Le Conte, John Eatton, 1784-1860
    D. 52 items. Various sizes. (see Le Conte papers.)
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], Jan. 21, 1848; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Schaum, Herm. Rud., (Hermann Rudolf), 1819-1865
    New Orleans, A.L.S. 4p.
  - Letter to J.[L.?] Le Conte, Jan. 27, 1848; 8 1/2" x 11"; Pease, William Harper, 1824-1872
    Jalapa, Mexico, A.L.S. 6p.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Jan. 31, 1848; 8-3/4x7; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Has ordered insects and gives forwarding address. Refers to Schaum.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Feb. 16, 1848; 7" x 8 1/2"; Dana, James Dwight, 1813-1895
    New Haven, A.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Feb. 16, 1848; 8-3/4x7; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    A.L.S.with initials. 4p. (see Le Conte papers.) Concerning the bushman and his language Wistar party visited. Academy of natural sciences publication. Ornithology and Wilson. Leidy and horses. Entomology. Rathvon's proposed expenses for 2 years. Refers to Agassiz and Horner.
  - Letter to J.[L.?] Le Conte, Feb. 21, 1848; 5 1/2" x 9"; Schaum, Herm. Rud., (Hermann Rudolf), 1819-1865
    New Orleans, A.L.S. 3p. and add.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, March 10, 1848; 7" x 9"; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    A.L.S. 3p. and add.
  - Letter to [J.L.?] Le C[onte], March 15, 1848; 7" x 9"; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    Columbia, Pa., A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], March 19, 1848; 7" x 8 3/4"; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, March 27, 1848; 7" x 8 3/4"; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    [ ] near Columbia, Pa., A.L.S. 3p. and add. Enc. - newsclipping.
  - Letter to John [L. Le conte], April 10, 1848; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Jones, W. L.
    Liberty, Georgia, A.L.S. 4p. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomology.of Georgia. Animals of Georgia. Itenerary of his projected trip. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], April 10, 1848; 4 1/2" x 6 3/4"; Schaum, Herm. Rud., (Hermann Rudolf), 1819-1865
    New Orl[eans] A.L.S. 11p.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], April 29, 1848; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Zimmerman, C.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, New York, May 4, 1848; 9-3/4x8; Jones, W. L.
    Liberty, Georgia, A.L.S. 3p.and add. (see Le Conte papers.) Natural history. Salamadders. Refers to collecting mollusks, Agassiz, Baird,etc Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], May 9, 1848; 5" x 8"; Schaum, Herm. Rud., (Hermann Rudolf), 1819-1865
    Cin[cinnati] A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], May 27, 1848; 8-3/4x7; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    Columbia, Penna., A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomology. Spiders. Natural history.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte]., May, 1848; 7-3/4x5; Schaum, Herm. Rud., (Hermann Rudolf), 1819-1865
    A.L.S. 2p. Incomplete. (see Le Conte papers.) Hopes to see him in Cleveland. Has forwarded box of insects.
  - Letter to [John L. LeConte], May, [18]48; 7-3/4 x 5. The upper left portion of the letter is torn away.; Schaum, Herm. Rud., (Hermann Rudolf), 1819-1865
  - Letter to John [L.] Leconte, July 7, 1848; 8" x 10"; Schaum, Herm. Rud., (Hermann Rudolf), 1819-1865
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. and add.
  - Letter to [John Eatton Le Conte?], July 14, 1848; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Informs him of Dr. Le Conte's health when last seen.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Aug. 3, 1848; 7" x 8 3/4"; Lacordaire, Théodore, 1801-1870
    Liege, A.L.S. 2p. In French.
  - Letter to J[ohn E.] Le Conte, New York, Aug. 16, 1848; 9x7-1/4; Schaum, Herm. Rud., (Hermann Rudolf), 1819-1865
    London, A.L.S. 3p.and add. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomology. Refers to John L. Le Conte. Originally B L493.4
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, Oct. 2, 1848; 5" x 8"; Thomson, James
    Geneva, A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], Oct. 15, 1848; 8" x 10"; Zimmerman, C.
    Columbia, A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Nov. 9, 1848; 8-1/2x5; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 1p.and end. (see Le Conte papers.) Will leave when he wishes. Asks him to notify a man from Europe of his leaving.
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, New York, Nov. 10, 1848; 11x8-3/4; Melly, André, 1802-1851
    Liverpool, A.L.S. 2p.,add. (see Le Conte papers.) Thanks for American insects. Entomological news. Refers to Agassiz.
  - Letter to John [L. Le Conte], Nov. 13, 1848; 8" x 10 1/2"; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887
    Carlisle, A.L.S. 1p. Contains also a note size by V (?) B. Blaney.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, New York, Nov. 24, 1848; 10x7-1/2; Harris, Thaddeus William, 1795-1856
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 3p.and add. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomology. Refers to Agassiz, Haldeman, and Melsheimer.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], Nov. 25, 1848; 5 1/2" x 8 1/2"; Schaum, Herm. Rud., (Hermann Rudolf), 1819-1865
    Halle, A.L.S. 4p.
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, Dec. 1, 1848; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Melsheimer, Friedrich Ernst, 1782-1873
    Dover, Pa., A.L.S. 3p. and add.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Dec. 7, 1848; 5-1/4x3-1/2; Busk, George, 1807-1886
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomology.
  - Letter to J.[L.?] Le Conte, Dec. 17, 1848; 9" x 11"; Pease, William Harper, 1824-1872
    New Orleans, A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to [J.L. Leconte], Jan. 23, 1849; 7 1/2" x 9 3/4"; Harris, Thaddeus William, 1795-1856
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 4p. P.PAN
    Returned to Academy of Natural Sciences, per note of Oct. 18, 1945.
  - Letter to J.[L.?] Le Conte, Jan. 26, 1849; 5 1/4" x 8 1/4"; Pease, William Harper, 1824-1872
    Panama, A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], Jan. 30, 1849; 5 1/2" x 8 1/2"; Lacordaire, Théodore, 1801-1870
    Liege, A.L.S. 4p. In French
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, Feb. 1, 1849; 4 1/2" x 7"; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    Columbia, Pa., A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to [John L. LeConte], ca. Jan. 1849; Harris, Thaddeus William, 1795-1856
    Returned to the Academy of Natural Sciences, per note of Oct. 18, 1945.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], Feb. 9, 1849; 7 3/4" x 10"; Morris, John G., (John Gottlieb), 1803-1895
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Feb. 19, 1849; 10x8; Burnett, W. J. (William J.), 1842-1930
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomology.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte?], March 29, 1849; 8" x 10"; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
  - Letter to [John L.] LeConte, Apr. 6, 1849; 8x10.; Morris, John G., (John Gottlieb), 1803-1895
    Requests information on entomologists in New York.
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, April 6, 1849 (?); 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Morris, John G., (John Gottlieb), 1803-1895
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], April 9, 1849; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Torrey, John, 1796-1873
    Princeton, A.L.S. 3p. (see Le Conte papers.) Concerning Charles Wilkes' treatment of scientists and his disagreement with him. Can do botany of certain areas of the expedition, but certainly not all the items Wilkes expects, including botany. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to J.[L.?] Le Conte, May 1, 1849; 8" x 10 1/2"; Pease, William Harper, 1824-1872
    San Francisco, A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], May 8, 1849; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Carter, E. James
    New York City, L. 4p.,end.: "S.S.Haldeman." (see Le Conte papers.) Sorry he has been ill. News of mutual friends.
  - Letter to Dr. [John L.] Le Conte, New York, June 2, 1849; 8x5; Melly, André, 1802-1851
    Liverpool, A.L.S. 2p.,end. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomological news.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], June 5, 1849; 8 1/2" x 11"; Schaum, Herm. Rud., (Hermann Rudolf), 1819-1865
    Berlin, A.L.S. 4p.
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, July 16, 1849; 8-3/4x5-1/2; Schaum, Herm. Rud., (Hermann Rudolf), 1819-1865
    Berlin, A.L.S. 2p.,with P.S.by A.Milly, dated (see Le Conte papers.) Concerning shipments of insects.
  - Letter to[J.L ?] Le Conte, July 18, 1849; 8" x 10 1/2"; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    Columbia,Pa., A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], Aug. 6, 1849; 7 1/2" x 9 1/2"; Zimmerman, C.
    Columbia, S.C., A.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to John L. LeConte, Aug. 24, 1849; 8-1/2 x 10-1/2
  - Letter to J.L. Leconte, Aug. 26, 1849; 6 3/4" x 8 1/4"; Gibbes, Robert W. (Robert Wilson), 1809-1866
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to John [L.] Le Conte, New York, Aug. 27, 1849; 10x8; Stout, Arthur B.
    Panama, A.L.S. 3p.and add. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomology. Natural history subjects. Refers to "Prof. Agassiz."
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, Sept. 6, 1849; 8" x 10"; Savage, Thomas Staughton, 1804-1880
    Sumterville, Ala., A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], Sept. 11, 1849; 7 1/2" x 9 3/4"; Potter, Howard
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], Sept. 28, 1849; 7 1/2" x 9 1/2"; Morris, John G., (John Gottlieb), 1803-1895
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 1p. and end.
  - Letter to [J.L.?] Le Conte, Sept. 28, 1849; 5 1/2" x 9"; Schaum, Herm. Rud., (Hermann Rudolf), 1819-1865
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, New York, Sept. 29, 1849; 10x8; Lincoln, Julia Kendall
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see Le Conte papers.) Proof of his book. Agassiz says that he [Le Conte] will furnish a plate for illustration.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], October 20, 1849; 5 1/4" x 8"; Lacordaire, Théodore, 1801-1870
    Liege, A.L.S. 4p.
  - Letter to [J.L.?] Le Conte, Dec. 10, 1849; 5 1/4" x 8 1/2"; Schaum, Herm. Rud., (Hermann Rudolf), 1819-1865
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Jan. 10, 1850; 8" x 10"; Hammond, Ogden
    Charleston, S.C., A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, March 23, 1850; 5" x 8"; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
  - Letter to [John Eatton LeConte], April 5, 1850; 5 1/2" x 9"; Schaum, Herm. Rud., (Hermann Rudolf), 1819-1865
  - Letter to [J.L.?] Leconte, May 11, 1850; 4 3/4" x 7 1/2"; Zimmerman, C.
    Columbia, S.C. A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to [John Eatton LeConte], May 11, 1850; 7-1/2 x 9-1/2; Zimmerman, C.
    Regarding John L. LeConte's work in California.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], July 12, 1850; 5 1/4" x 8 1/4"; Lacordaire, Théodore, 1801-1870
    Liege, A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to Major [J. E. Le Conte ?], Dec. 4, 1850; 4 3/4" x 7 1/2"; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    Columbia, Pa., A.L.S. 4p.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], Dec. 16, 1850; 8x4; Melsheimer, Friedrich Ernst, 1782-1873
    Dover Township, Penna., A.L.S. 4p. (see Le Conte Papers) Questions concerning coleoptera.
  - Letter to John [Eatton?] Le Conte, Feb. 12, 1851; 8 1/4" x 10 3/4"; Engelmann, George, 1809-1884
    St. Louis, A.L.S. 3p. and add.
  - Letter to J[ohn Eatton] Leconte, Feb. 25, 1851; 5 1/4" x 8"; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to [John Eatton Le Conte ?], March 12, 1851; 5" x 8"; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
  - Letter to J.[L.?] Le Conte, March 12, 1851; 8 1/4" x 10 1/2"; Pease, William Harper, 1824-1872
    Kauai (?), A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to John [Eatton] Le Conte, April (?) 18, 1851; 5" x 7 1/2"; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    Columbia, Pa., A.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to John [Eatton] Le Conte, June 29, 1851; 5 1/4" x 8"; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887
  - Letter to [John Eatton Le Conte], July 7, 1851; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte?], July 24, 1851; 8 1/4" x 10 1/2"; Zimmerman, C.
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, July 28, 1851; 5" x 8"; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, Aug. 3, 1851; 8 1/4" x 10 3/4"; Zimmerman, C.
    Columbia, S.C., A.L.S. 1p. and add.
  - Letter to John [Eatton] Leconte, Aug. 7, 1851; 7 1/2" x 9 1/2"; Harris, Thaddeus William, 1795-1856
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to Major John [Eatton ?] Leconte, Aug. 28, 1851; 7 1/4" x 9 3/4"; Harris, Thaddeus William, 1795-1856
  - Letter to John L. Leconte, Sept. 10, 1851; 7 1/2" x 9 3/4"; Harris, Thaddeus William, 1795-1856
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 3P.
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. LeConte, Sept. 12, [1851]; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Abbott, Asa M
    Hemlo, Whiteside co., Ill., A.L.S. 2p. Asks for details about the circumstances of the Oatman murders and the likelihood of the daughters' survival.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], Sept. 13, 1851; 5 1/2" x 9"; Engelmann, George, 1809-1884
    St. Louis, A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, Sept. 17, 1851; 5" x 8"; Bayley, James Roosevelt, 1814-1877
    New York, A.L.S. 4p.
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, Oct. 1, 1851; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Randall, A.
    San Francisco, A.L.S. 3p. and add.
    Location unknown - empty Aug. 8, 1962.
  - Letter to John L. Leconte, Oct. 13, 1851; 7 1/2" x 9 3/4"; Harris, Thaddeus William, 1795-1856
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 4p. (small slip enclosed) PPAN
    Returned to Academy of Natural Science - October 18, 1945
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], October 15, 1851; 5 1/4" x 8 1/4"; Lacordaire, Théodore, 1801-1870
    Liege, A.L.S. 5p.
  - Letter to Andrés Poey, Oct. 16, 1851; 6" x 8 3/4"; Poey, Felipe, 1799-1891
    Havana, A.L.S. 3p. and add. In French.
  - Letter to J.L. Leconte, Oct. 21, 1851; 7 1/2" x 9 3/4"; Harris, Thaddeus William, 1795-1856
    Returned to the Academy of Natural Science - October 18, 1945
  - List of California species for Lacordaire, Oct., 1851; 10 x 7-3/4; LeConte, John L., (John Lawrence), 1825-1883
    List of 90 items.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], Nov. 2, 1851; 8 1/4" x 10 1/2"; Zimmerman, C.
  - Letter to John [Eatton] Leconte, Nov. 8, 1851; 5 1/4" x 8"; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887
  - Letter to John L. Leconte, Nov. 25, 1851; 7 1/4" x 9 3/4"; Harris, Thaddeus William, 1795-1856
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 4p.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, New York, Nov. 29, 1851; 10x8; Gould & Lincoln
    Boston, L. 2p. (see Le Conte papers.) Concerning a publication by Aggasiz.
  - Letter to J. L. Leconte, Dec. 6, 1851; 7 1/2" x 9 3/4"; Harris, Thaddeus William, 1795-1856
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 4p. PPAN
    Returned to Academy of Natural Sciences - October 18, 1945
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], Dec. 29, 1851; 8 1/4" x 10 1/2"; Poey, Felipe, 1799-1891
    Havana, A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to Thomas Watson, Dec. 31, 1851; 10x8; Spring, J. H.
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p.and end. (see Le Conte papers.) Orders tortoise shells.
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, Jan. 2, 1852; 8x5; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers Will keep after Henry and Wilkes to get the business done. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to John [L?] Le Conte, Jan. 8, 1852; 5" x 8"; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, Jan. 12, 1852; 11x8-1/2; Haldeman, Samuel Stehman, 1812-1880
    Selma, Ala., A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte Papers.) Has become "head" of a college in Alabama. Entomology. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to Jo[h]n L. Le Conte, Jan. 15, 1852; 12x7-1/2; Rathvon, S. S., (Simon Snyder), 1812-1891
    Lancaster, [Penna.], A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Forwards natural history specimens from the West and is disappointed over specimens, especially insects. Refers to Haldeman.
  - Letter to Jo[h]n L. Le Conte, New York, Jan. 19, 1852; 8x5-1/4; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte Papers.) Entomological specimens. Smithsonian news. Refers to Haldeman and Henry. Refers to wilkes' exploring expedition. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to Jno. L. Le Conte, Feb. 12, 1852; 4 3/4" x 7 1/4"; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, Feb. 17, 1852; 5 1/4" x 8 1/2"; Lacordaire, Théodore, 1801-1870
    Liege, A.L.S. 3p. and add. In French.
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, Feb. 21, 1852; 5 1/4" x 8"; Dana, James Dwight, 1813-1895
    New Haven, A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to J[ohn L.] Le Conte, Philadelphia, April 15, 1852; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Campbell, Albert H. (Albert Henry), 1826-1899
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p.and end. (see Le Conte papers.) Concerning a manuscript.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], April 23, 1852; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Chaudoir, M. de (Maximilien), baron, 1817-1881
    L. 4p. In French. (see Le Conte papers). California entomology.
  - Letter to J.L. Le Conte, April 28, 1852; 8" x 10 1/2"; Schaum, Herm. Rud., (Hermann Rudolf), 1819-1865
    Berlin, A.L.S. 4p.,add.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte ?], May 2, 1852; 5" x 8"; Hall, James, 1811-1898
    Albany, (?) A.L.S. 4p.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], May 6, 1852; 10x7-3/4; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873
    Cambridge Mass., A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Concerning crayfishes.
  - Letter to[J.L. Le Conte ?], May 20, 1852; 5 1/2" x 8 1/2"; Lacordaire, Théodore, 1801-1870
    Liege, A.L.S. 4p. In French.